<resources xmlns:xliff="urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:1.2">
    <string name="matt4_18_22">18 As Jesus walked along the shore of Lake Galilee, he saw two brothers who were fishermen, Simon (called Peter) and his brother Andrew, catching fish in the lake with a net.\n
        19 Jesus said to them, “Come with me, and I will teach you to catch people.”\n
        20 At once they left their nets and went with him.\n
        21 He went on and saw two other brothers, James and John, the sons of Zebedee. They were in their boat with their father Zebedee, getting their nets ready. Jesus called them,\n
        22 and at once they left the boat and their father, and went with him.</string>
<string name="matt28_18_20">18 Jesus drew near and said to them, “I have been given all authority in heaven and on earth.\n
19 Go, then, to all peoples everywhere and make them my disciples: baptize them in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit,\n
20 and teach them to obey everything I have commanded you. And I will be with you always, to the end of the age.”
</string>
<string name="matt19_16_22">16 Just then a man came up to Jesus and asked, “Teacher, what good thing must I do to get eternal life?” \n
17 “Why do you ask me about what is good?” Jesus replied. “There is only One who is good. If you want to enter life, keep the commandments.”\n
18 “Which ones?” he inquired.\n
Jesus replied, “‘You shall not murder, you shall not commit adultery, you shall not steal, you shall not give false testimony, 19 honor your father and mother,’ and ‘love your neighbor as yourself.’”\n
20 “All these I have kept,” the young man said. “What do I still lack?”\n
21 Jesus answered, “If you want to be perfect, go, sell your possessions and give to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven. Then come, follow me.”\n
22 When the young man heard this, he went away sad, because he had great wealth.</string>
<string name="matt19_21_22">
21 Jesus answered, “If you want to be perfect, go, sell your possessions and give to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven. Then come, follow me.”\n
22 When the young man heard this, he went away sad, because he had great wealth.</string>
    <string name="mark16_17_1820">
        17 Believers will be given the power to perform miracles: they will drive out demons in my name; they will speak in strange tongues;\n
        18if they pick up snakes or drink any poison, they will not be harmed; they will place their hands on sick people, who will get well.”\n
        20 The disciples went and preached everywhere, and the Lord worked with them and proved that their preaching was true by the miracles that were performed.
    </string>
<string name="luke_8_4_15">
4 People kept coming to Jesus from one town after another; and when a great crowd gathered, Jesus told this parable:\n
5 “Once there was a man who went out to sow corn. As he scattered the seed in the field, some of it fell along the path, where it was stepped on, and the birds ate it up\n
6 Some of it fell on rocky ground, and when the plants sprouted, they dried up because the soil had no moisture.\n
7 Some of the seed fell among thorn bushes, which grew up with the plants and choked them.\n
8 And some seeds fell in good soil; the plants grew and produced corn, a hundred each.” And Jesus concluded, “Listen, then, if you have ears!”
9 His disciples asked Jesus what this parable meant, \n
10 and he answered, “The knowledge of the secrets of the Kingdom of God has been given to you, but to the rest it comes by means of parables, so that they may look but not see, and listen but not understand.\n
11 “This is what the parable means: the seed is the word of God.
12The seeds that fell along the path stand for those who hear; but the Devil comes and takes the message away from their hearts in order to keep them from believing and being saved.
13 The seeds that fell on rocky ground stand for those who hear the message and receive it gladly. But it does not sink deep into them; they believe only for a while but when the time of testing comes, they fall away.
14 The seeds that fell among thorn bushes stand for those who hear; but the worries and riches and pleasures of this life crowd in and choke them, and their fruit never ripens.
15 The seeds that fell in good soil stand for those who hear the message and retain it in a good and obedient heart, and they persist until they bear fruit.</string>
</resources>