<resources>
<string name="t"><![CDATA[<b>The Starting Point of John’s Gospel</b><br>
	John the Baptist was the forerunner of Jesus. He was Jesus’ cousin, born 6 months earlier than Jesus, and was from birth bestowed the ministry of introducing Jesus to the world, preparing the people to receive Jesus’ ministry. The Bible in <a href="">Mark 1:1-8</a> describes John’s ministry using the following words: He was God’s messenger sent before Jesus to prepare the way for Jesus. He came to baptise in the wilderness and preach a baptism of <b><i>repentance</i><b> for the remission (or complete cancellation and forgiveness) of sins. <a href="">Matthew 3:2</a> records John preaching “<b><i>Repent</i></b> for the kingdom of heaven is at hand!” <br><br>
The Starting Point of Jesus’ Gospel<br><br>
Then when Jesus began his ministry, His message had similar introductory words too! For example, <a href="">Matthew 4:7</a> records that “From that time Jesus began to preach and to say, “Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” Also in <a href="">Mark 1:15</a> Jesus preached “The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand. Repent, and believe in the gospel.”<br><br>
<b>Meaning of Repent</b><br>
As a new Christian believer it is vital to “repent”. What is the meaning of “to repent”, what is “repentance”? The various definitions are:<br>
&#8226;Dictionary defines repentance as “the action of repenting, sincere regret, sincere remorse.” <br>
&#8226;Cambridge English Dictionary defines repentance as “to be very sorry for something bad you have done in the past and wish that you had not done it”<br>
&#8226;The Greek word for repent is the verb “metanoeo” (metanoevw) and the noun “metanoia” (metavnoia), and reference to “repent” and “repentance” occur about 54 times in the New Testament. The 2 usual senses are “a change of mind” and “regret or remorse”.<br>
&#8226;In the Old Testament, the references to “repent” is to “turn” or “return”, “to turn away from evil, and to turn to the good”. <br><br>
John’s message to the people was one of “turning away from sin” and breaking away from the old and turning to God. John went further to require the people to be baptised in water for repentance (<a href="">Mark 1:4</a>,<a href="">Luke 3:3</a>) and afterwards show “fruits of repentance” (<a href="">Luke 3:10-14</a>) by the changed attitudes hearts and deeds.

!]]>
</string>
<string name="chapter2"><![CDATA[<b><font size="6">Introduction – Jesus’ Call to “Follow Me”</font></b><br>
It was God’s plan from the beginning to send Jesus to the earth, even though He was (and is) God, yet to live as a man, and to die on the cross for our sin as the lamb sacrifice. Jesus’ blood washes us of all our sin. <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Rev/13/8/">Revelation 13:8 </a> declares that Jesus is the Lamb slain from the foundation of the world. Therefore, Jesus had a plan to execute and an objective to accomplish. His life on earth was intentional and full of purpose. <br><br>

Even though Jesus’ ministry lasted a short 3.5 years, part of His plan included calling and making disciples.<br><br>
At the beginning of His ministry, <a href="matt4_18_22">Matthew 4:18-22 </a>recorded how Jesus called his first 4 disciples, who were businessman running a “fishing” business. He saw 2 brothers Simon Peter and Andrew and said to them, “Follow Me, and I will make you fishers of men.” They immediately left their nets and followed Him. He saw another 2 brothers James and John and called them, and immediately they left the boat and their father, and followed Him. <br>
The observation is as follows: <br>
	 &#10004;Jesus called the men, saying “Follow Me”. <br>
	 &#10004;Jesus gave them His (new) vision and mission being “I will make you fishermen of people” (as opposed to fish). <br>
	 &#10004;Their response was immediate, and they each left their current work and family, and followed Jesus into the new vision and mission that He told them about. <br><br>
Their response tells me that they believed in Jesus and His vision and mission for them; they were confident in His Word, they did not doubt! <br><br>

<b>Meaning of “Follow”</b><br>
Google dictionary says “go or come after a person proceeding ahead; move or travel behind.” <br><br>

Cambridge English dictionary says “to move behind someone and go where he goes.” <br><br>

Essentially, Jesus gave an invitation to the 4 men to leave their then current way of life, and to ‘follow’ Him, to be with Him, to spend their daily lifetime with Him. It is throughout the day and during this time of togetherness that the 4 men can observe Jesus, watch His ways, learn His values, have many conversations and discussions about life and all of life’s contents. It is also out of this constant close association and fellowship that Jesus can teach these 4 men, correct, counsel, explain God’s ways and God’s will. <br>

This effectively is the process of ‘making disciples’; it is a lifestyle process, it is a close association and learning journey of the disciple maker and disciple, walking out life together. The disciple maker moulding and shaping the disciple according to the image and likeness and pattern of God <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Gen/1/28/">Genesis 1:28</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Isa/64/8/">Isaiah 64:8</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/2Cor/3/18/">2 Corinthians 3:18</a>. <br>
Therefore Jesus was the disciple maker (or discipler) and He made disciples out of the men who followed Him. <br>

<b>God has Given the Call to You to “Follow Him” </b><br>
<a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/2Tim/1/9/">2 Timothy 1:9 </a > says that God “has saved us and called us with a holy calling, according to His own purpose and grace which was given to us in Christ Jesus before time began”. This scripture clearly tells us that God has called us according to His purpose. Just like Jesus called His disciples for a purpose. Do you know what is that purpose? <br><br>
<a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Rev/17/14/">Revelation 17:14</a> says “those who are with Him are called, chosen, and faithful”. Those who follow Jesus are indeed “with Him”. Who would give up the opportunity to be with Jesus? <br>
God’s call is to everyone to follow Him, to leave behind the former way of life, the former way of thinking, the former conduct, even the former way of conducting business, and to follow Him. Follow His way of life, His way of thinking, His conduct, His way of conducting business. <br><br>

Did you know that even though God’s call has been given to everyone, not everyone will respond?! Not everyone will follow Him! Jesus said that many are called, but few are chosen <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Matt/20/16/">Matthew 20:16</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Matt/22/14/">22:14</a>. This does not mean that God only chooses a few. It properly means that few respond to God’s call. Also, of the ones that respond to God’s call, some will drop off because of various reasons. For example, Jesus called the rich young ruler to “come, follow Me” but he “went away sorrowful” and did not follow Jesus<a href="matt19_16_22"> Matthew 19:16-22</a>. <br><br>

These are some of the reasons that people fail to follow Jesus, or to remain faithful to the end in the following of Jesus: <br>

&#8226;In the case of the rich young ruler, he had great possessions and could not make the decision to sell everything that he had and give it to the poor, and that inability stopped him from following Jesus <a href="matt19_21_22">Matthew 19:21-22</a>. For this chap, he could not repent; he could not let go of his material wealth, he could not leave behind all his possessions, and these material things prevented him from following Jesus. <br>

&#8226;Some other reasons could be<a href="luke_8_4_15"> Luke 8:4-15</a><br>
	&#8212;demonic influence (seed that fall by the wayside)<br>
	o	temptation causes one to fall away, because lacking good deep roots in the things of God (seed that fall on rock)<br>
	o	life’s cares, riches, pleasures choke the life of God and therefore no fruit and no maturity (seed that fall among thorns)<br><br>
<b>Passing the Baton</b><br>
We know that Jesus called his disciples to follow Him. Did you also know that Jesus has called you (and me) to send the call out to others (all kinds and all types, from all parts of the world) to follow us <a href="matt28_18_20"> Matthew 28:18-20</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/John/20/21/">John 20:21</a>? <br><br>
Jesus called 4 men to “Follow Him” => 4 men became His disciples => 4 men to go make disciples of all nations<br><br>

<b>Jesus’ Example</b><br>
Jesus taught His disciples to follow Him. He taught the disciples and the multitudes through different ways, such as in parables, using life issues, addressed money and finance. He served people, He healed the sick, He prayed, He did many miracles. These are some aspects of Jesus’ life, as an example for us to follow:<br>
a.	Jesus was obedient to His Father – He only did what He saw His Father doing <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/John/5/30/">John 5:30</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/John/8/28/">8:28</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/John/10/18/">10:18</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/John/10/25/">25</a> <br>
b.	Jesus prayed<br>
c.	Jesus relied on the Word of God for His sustenance and to overcome evil <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Matt/4/4/">Matthew 4:4</a><br>
d.	Looked after His family (biological and spiritual) <br>
e.	Jesus mixed around with all types and all kinds of people (cf not only people who He preferred) <br>
f.	Considered the needs of people, strangers<br>
g.	Paid His taxes properly<br>
h.	Did not condone or put up with religious practices, which He considered to be hypocritical and deceitful<br>
i.	Desired unity, love, peace<br>
a.	Performed miracles signs and wonders (we must learn to live out the power of God in and through our lives daily<a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/John/14/12/"> John 14:12</a>, <a href="mark16_17_1820"> Mark 16:17-18, 20</a>) <br><br>
We must decide once and for all, will be respond immediately to God’s call upon our lives, to follow Him, or not. The decision must be firm, definite, permanent. The decision cannot be wishy washy, half-hearted, compromised, weak, indefinite, short-term. Some people will say ‘yes’ but mean ‘no’ in their minds and hearts. In order for anyone to properly follow Jesus, the decision must be to “repent” from the former things, and start on a new course, a new direction, a new way of life. There must be a change of heart and mind, there must be a letting go and putting off of the past. There cannot be a turning back or regret once one moves forward into the new way of life and living in Christ. <br> <br>

<b>Who Are You Following? </b><br><br>
It is important for you (and me) to ask these questions of ourselves. It is necessary to take some time to self-examine. Am I following Jesus? Am I a follower of Jesus? Is my life patterned after Jesus’ life? Are my values principles and convictions the same as that of Jesus? Do I search the Word of God to obey God’s commands and instructions? <br><br>
Am I following the world’s ways? Do I fashion myself after what I see and hear on screens (movies, internet, online chat applications)? Have I made the values of media become my values (drama series, journalists who report the news with their versions and views)? Do I follow well known personalities (politicians, movie actors, singers, dancers, performers)? <br>
Jesus left earth a little over 2,000 years ago and returned to His heavenly abode <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Mark/16/19/">Mark 16:19</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Luke/24/51/">Luke 24:51</a>. He commissioned His disciples to continue going about making disciples. Therefore today, we “follow Jesus” by following these: <br><br>
1.	The Word of God both Old and New Testaments as this is the will of God comprised and preserved for our knowledge observance and life. The Word of God is our manual of the life in Christ. There is so much treasure and truth in God’s Word. There is life and light and power in God’s written promises. We must search the Scriptures with a hungry and thirsty attitude to find the truth that will help us to live out this godly Christian life with success and fulfilment. <br>
2.	Jesus’ life as recorded in the books of the Bible written by His disciples Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John. <br>
3.	Church community – elders, pastors, brothers and sisters who fellowship and encourage one another. It is vital for a Christian to find a church community that is good and conducive for growth unto maturity. <br><br>
<font color="#ff0000">Practical - Prayer</font><br>
Practical steps include making a commitment to attend church meetings where the Word of God is preached and taught for the objective of helping you become a mature son or daughter of God. <br>
Suggested Prayer is as follows: <br>
Dear Heavenly Father, I thank You for calling me to follow Jesus. Right now, I decide to “Follow Jesus”, to obey Your Word, to stay in fellowship with brothers and sisters who together we can grow unto maturity. Help me to be a good disciple. Help me to learn Your Word, and Your Will, and Your ways. In time, help me to go and make disciples. In Jesus’ Name I ask. Amen.

!]]>
</string>
    <string name="chapter3"></string>
</resources>