<resources>
<string name="Repent"><![CDATA[<b>The Starting Point of John’s Gospel</b><br><br>
John the Baptist was the forerunner of Jesus. He was Jesus’ cousin, born 6 months earlier than Jesus, and was from birth bestowed the ministry of introducing Jesus to the world, preparing the people to receive Jesus’ ministry. The Bible in <a href="41_1_1-8">Mark 1:1-8</a> describes John’s ministry using the following words: He was God’s messenger sent before Jesus to prepare the way for Jesus. He came to baptise in the wilderness and preach a baptism of <b><i>repentance</i></b> for the remission (or complete cancellation and forgiveness) of sins. <a href="40_3_2">Matthew 3:2</a> records John preaching “<b><i>Repent</i></b> for the kingdom of heaven is at hand!” <br><br>
<b>The Starting Point of Jesus’ Gospel</b><br><br>
Then when Jesus began his ministry, His message had similar introductory words too! For example, <a href="40_4_7">Matthew 4:7</a> records that “From that time Jesus began to preach and to say, “Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” Also in <a href="41_1_15">Mark 1:15</a> Jesus preached “The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand. Repent, and believe in the gospel.”<br><br>
<b>Meaning of Repent</b><br>
As a new Christian believer it is vital to “repent”. What is the meaning of “to repent”, what is “repentance”? The various definitions are:<br>
&#8226;Dictionary defines repentance as “the action of repenting, sincere regret, sincere remorse.” <br>
&#8226;Cambridge English Dictionary defines repentance as “to be very sorry for something bad you have done in the past and wish that you had not done it”<br>
&#8226;The Greek word for repent is the verb “metanoeo” (metanoevw) and the noun “metanoia” (metavnoia), and reference to “repent” and “repentance” occur about 54 times in the New Testament. The 2 usual senses are “a change of mind” and “regret or remorse”.<br>
&#8226;In the Old Testament, the references to “repent” is to “turn” or “return”, “to turn away from evil, and to turn to the good”. <br><br>
John’s message to the people was one of “turning away from sin” and breaking away from the old and turning to God. John went further to require the people to be baptised in water for repentance (<a href="41_1_4">Mark 1:4</a>,<a href="42_3_3">Luke 3:3</a>) and afterwards show “fruits of repentance” (<a href="42_3_10-14">Luke 3:10-14</a>) by the changed attitudes hearts and deeds.<br><br>
Some examples from the Bible of people who repented are as follows: <br><br>
1.	John gave specific ways of how people could show the fruits, or practical consequences, of their repentance. In <a href="42_3_10-14">Luke 3:10-14</a> he taught that <br>
a.	People (everyone) who had more than what they needed should share their possession and provision with those who did not have, “give to the hungry, clothe the poor, bless the needy”. <br>
b.	Workers (tax collectors) ought to do the right thing and not exploit their position of power to acquire more for themselves at the expense of other, “be honest”. <br>
c.	government employees (soldiers) ought to be content with one’s wages and not use their position of power to intimidate exploit or extort for the purpose of personal gain, also not accuse falsely, intimidate or terrify others by threats of violence, not accuse the innocent, for the objective of gaining an advantage over others in their care. <br>
2.	Jesus taught the story of the prodigal son in <a href="40_21_29">Matthew 21:29</a> and how the son “changed his mind” about doing his father’s bidding. <br>
3.	In <a href="40_27_3">Matthew 27:3</a>, Judas Iscariot was “seized with remorse” after betraying Jesus. <br>
4.	Paul in <a href="47_7_8-10">2 Corinthians 7:8-10</a> said he did not regret the sorrow caused to his readers by his letters, and did not regret the pain that brought “repentance” that leads to salvation. <br><br>
<b>Why Repent? </b><br><br>
When people make a conscious decision to believe in Jesus, believe in the gospel (story) of Jesus, desire to commence a relationship with Almighty God and follow His ways, the Bible says that people are suddenly translated from the kingdom of darkness into the kingdom of light. The kingdom of light is God’s kingdom. The kingdom of darkness comprises everything worldly, carnal, demonic. This realm of living comprises values and principles that are contrary to the realm of living in God’s kingdom. One must accept the truth that that cannot be any mixture or compromise between the 2 kingdoms. In other words, it is not possible or practical for one to have 1 foot in the kingdom of darkness and 1 foot in the kingdom of light. If this is the case, then the writer would venture to say that such a person is more likely to be living out of the kingdom of darkness, but trying to live in the kingdom of light, and this person will end up confused, frustrated, disillusioned, or a weak Christian. <br><br>
Having lived in the kingdom of darkness for a long while, and then suddenly coming into the kingdom of light, it is vital for one to be willing to start on a clean slate, to ‘start from scratch’ so to speak. It is vital for one to be willing to understand God’s kingdom, His ways, His will, His rules, and to start living accordingly to God’s kingdom economy, and therefore ‘repentance’ or a change of one’s heart mind attitude direction and life’s destiny is necessary. <br><br>
Jesus taught that one cannot add new wine into old wineskins. The new wine will cause the old wineskins to tear and break, and finally both the new wine and old wineskins will be lost. However, new wine (new teachings, new ways) must be put into new wineskins (repented people). <br><br>
People who try to live as Christians but without having first repented, will face great difficulty in accepting the ways and will of God. Some Christians can attend church meetings and services for many years and still find it difficult to breakthrough into an experience of victory, peace, and miracles. Repentant at the ‘get go’ is the key. <br><br>
<b>Repent From What? </b> <br><br>
Repent from <br>
&#8226;Lack of faith, lack of belief => dare to believe, pray and ask God to help our unbelief <a href="41_9_24">Mark 9:24</a>, <a href="58_10_38">Hebrews 10:38</a><br>
&#8226;Stubborn, stiff-necked <a href="43_7_51_">Acts 7:51</a> => be humble, be responsive to God’s call, instructions, commands, specific directive words<br>
&#8226;Disobedience <a href="49_2_2">Ephesians 2:2</a> => obedient, teachable, good learner, good student <br>
&#8226;Evil ways, evil deeds, evil intentions => motive and conduct are to be radically changed to become godly and reflective of God’s will and God’s ways <a href="Isa1_16_17">Isaiah 1:16-17</a>, <a href="26_14_6">Ezekiel 14:6</a>, <a href="26_18_30">18:30</a>, <a href="26_33_11"> 33:11</a><br>
&#8226;Futile mind <a href="49_4_17">Ephesians 4:17</a> => renewed mind according to God’s will and God’s word, transformed life with good deeds pleasing to the Lord <a href="45_12_1-2">Romans 12:1-2</a><br><br>

<b>How to Repent</b><br><br>
1.	Confession of sins <a href="62_1_9">1 John 1:9</a>, <a href="3_5_5"> Leviticus 5:5</a>, <a href="3_26_40-42">26:40-42</a>, <a href="14_7_14">2 Chronicles 7:14</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Ps/25/">Psalm 25</a>, <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Ps/51/">Psalm 51</a> => repentance and God’s forgiveness, healing<br>
2.	Stop the walk of old (futile mind, darkened understanding, separated from life of God, ignorant, blind heart, devoid of feeling, given to sinful and greedy ways, given to doing unclean work) <a href="49_4_17-19">Ephesians 4:17-19</a>, <a href="46_5_17">1 Corinthians 5:17</a><br>
3.	Learn Christ, experience Jesus <a href="49_20-21">Ephesians 4:20-21</a><br>
4.	Put off the old man, the former conduct, sinful and deceitful desires => put on the new man, the new creation (born again by God’s Spirit according to God, in true righteousness and true holiness) <a href="49_5_22-5_21">Ephesians 4:22-5:21</a><br>
5.	Be renewed in attitude, in mind <a href="45_12_1-2">Romans 12:1-2</a><br>
6.	Ask God to help in all things. The Holy Spirit lives in you and is with you ready to help you to live life according to God’s will and God’s ways, and with God’s power and divine ability <a href="44_14_15-18">John 14:15-18</a>, <a href="43_15_26">15:26</a>, <a href="62_2_20-27">1 John 2:20-27</a><br>

<b>Fruits of Repentance</b><br><br>
When one repents and starts to walk out a repentant life, living with a repentant mind, heart, will, one will immediately start to bear fruits of repentance that John the Baptist spoke about in <a href="40_3_8">Matthew 3:8</a>. <br><br>
<font color="#ff0000">Practical</font><br><br>
This is a suggested prayer to God for repentance: <br>
Dear Heavenly Father, I come to you in the Name of Jesus Christ my Lord and Saviour. I acknowledge that I am wrong / ignorant / gone my own way / done my own thing, which is contrary to You and Your will and Your ways. I am sorry. I ask for your forgiveness and to cleanse me with the blood of Jesus. <br>
Thank You for accepting me in the Beloved. Thank You that there is no condemnation because I am in Christ. You are My Father, and I am Your child. I ask for your help, because I want to start living according to Your will and Your Word from now on. I want to repent and bear fruits worthy of repentance. So by the power of Your Holy Spirit, lead me and guide me. Speak to me and show me from Your Word, what I must do to change my mind and my way of life. Thank you. Amen. <br>
]]>
</string>
<string name="Follow_Jesus"><![CDATA[<b><font size="6">Introduction – Jesus’ Call to “Follow Me”</font></b><br>
It was God’s plan from the beginning to send Jesus to the earth, even though He was (and is) God, yet to live as a man, and to die on the cross for our sin as the lamb sacrifice. Jesus’ blood washes us of all our sin. <a href="66_13_8">Revelation 13:8 </a> declares that Jesus is the Lamb slain from the foundation of the world. Therefore, Jesus had a plan to execute and an objective to accomplish. His life on earth was intentional and full of purpose. <br><br>

Even though Jesus’ ministry lasted a short 3.5 years, part of His plan included calling and making disciples.<br><br>
At the beginning of His ministry, <a href="40_4_18-22">Matthew 4:18-22 </a>recorded how Jesus called his first 4 disciples, who were businessman running a “fishing” business. He saw 2 brothers Simon Peter and Andrew and said to them, “Follow Me, and I will make you fishers of men.” They immediately left their nets and followed Him. He saw another 2 brothers James and John and called them, and immediately they left the boat and their father, and followed Him. <br>
The observation is as follows: <br>
	 &#10004;Jesus called the men, saying “Follow Me”. <br>
	 &#10004;Jesus gave them His (new) vision and mission being “I will make you fishermen of people” (as opposed to fish). <br>
	 &#10004;Their response was immediate, and they each left their current work and family, and followed Jesus into the new vision and mission that He told them about. <br><br>
Their response tells me that they believed in Jesus and His vision and mission for them; they were confident in His Word, they did not doubt! <br><br>

<b>Meaning of “Follow”</b><br>
Google dictionary says “go or come after a person proceeding ahead; move or travel behind.” <br><br>

Cambridge English dictionary says “to move behind someone and go where he goes.” <br><br>

Essentially, Jesus gave an invitation to the 4 men to leave their then current way of life, and to ‘follow’ Him, to be with Him, to spend their daily lifetime with Him. It is throughout the day and during this time of togetherness that the 4 men can observe Jesus, watch His ways, learn His values, have many conversations and discussions about life and all of life’s contents. It is also out of this constant close association and fellowship that Jesus can teach these 4 men, correct, counsel, explain God’s ways and God’s will. <br>

This effectively is the process of ‘making disciples’; it is a lifestyle process, it is a close association and learning journey of the disciple maker and disciple, walking out life together. The disciple maker moulding and shaping the disciple according to the image and likeness and pattern of God <a href="1_1_28">Genesis 1:28</a>, <a href="23_64_8">Isaiah 64:8</a>, <a href="47_3_18">2 Corinthians 3:18</a>. <br>
Therefore Jesus was the disciple maker (or discipler) and He made disciples out of the men who followed Him. <br>

<b>God has Given the Call to You to “Follow Him” </b><br>
<a href="55_1_9">2 Timothy 1:9 </a > says that God “has saved us and called us with a holy calling, according to His own purpose and grace which was given to us in Christ Jesus before time began”. This scripture clearly tells us that God has called us according to His purpose. Just like Jesus called His disciples for a purpose. Do you know what is that purpose? <br><br>
<a href="66_17_14">Revelation 17:14</a> says “those who are with Him are called, chosen, and faithful”. Those who follow Jesus are indeed “with Him”. Who would give up the opportunity to be with Jesus? <br>
God’s call is to everyone to follow Him, to leave behind the former way of life, the former way of thinking, the former conduct, even the former way of conducting business, and to follow Him. Follow His way of life, His way of thinking, His conduct, His way of conducting business. <br><br>

Did you know that even though God’s call has been given to everyone, not everyone will respond?! Not everyone will follow Him! Jesus said that many are called, but few are chosen <a href="40_20_16">Matthew 20:16</a>, <a href="40_22_14">22:14</a>. This does not mean that God only chooses a few. It properly means that few respond to God’s call. Also, of the ones that respond to God’s call, some will drop off because of various reasons. For example, Jesus called the rich young ruler to “come, follow Me” but he “went away sorrowful” and did not follow Jesus<a href="40_19_16-22"> Matthew 19:16-22</a>. <br><br>

These are some of the reasons that people fail to follow Jesus, or to remain faithful to the end in the following of Jesus: <br>

&#8226;In the case of the rich young ruler, he had great possessions and could not make the decision to sell everything that he had and give it to the poor, and that inability stopped him from following Jesus <a href="40_19_21-22">Matthew 19:21-22</a>. For this chap, he could not repent; he could not let go of his material wealth, he could not leave behind all his possessions, and these material things prevented him from following Jesus. <br>

&#8226;Some other reasons could be<a href="42_8_4-15"> Luke 8:4-15</a><br>
	&#8212;demonic influence (seed that fall by the wayside)<br>
	o	temptation causes one to fall away, because lacking good deep roots in the things of God (seed that fall on rock)<br>
	o	life’s cares, riches, pleasures choke the life of God and therefore no fruit and no maturity (seed that fall among thorns)<br><br>
<b>Passing the Baton</b><br>
We know that Jesus called his disciples to follow Him. Did you also know that Jesus has called you (and me) to send the call out to others (all kinds and all types, from all parts of the world) to follow us <a href="40_28_18-20"> Matthew 28:18-20</a>, <a href="43_20_21">John 20:21</a>? <br><br>
Jesus called 4 men to “Follow Him” => 4 men became His disciples => 4 men to go make disciples of all nations<br><br>

<b>Jesus’ Example</b><br>
Jesus taught His disciples to follow Him. He taught the disciples and the multitudes through different ways, such as in parables, using life issues, addressed money and finance. He served people, He healed the sick, He prayed, He did many miracles. These are some aspects of Jesus’ life, as an example for us to follow:<br>
a.	Jesus was obedient to His Father – He only did what He saw His Father doing <a href="43_5_30">John 5:30</a>, <a href="43_8_28">8:28</a>, <a href="43_10_18">10:18</a>, <a href="43_10_25">25</a> <br>
b.	Jesus prayed<br>
c.	Jesus relied on the Word of God for His sustenance and to overcome evil <a href="40_4_4">Matthew 4:4</a><br>
d.	Looked after His family (biological and spiritual) <br>
e.	Jesus mixed around with all types and all kinds of people (cf not only people who He preferred) <br>
f.	Considered the needs of people, strangers<br>
g.	Paid His taxes properly<br>
h.	Did not condone or put up with religious practices, which He considered to be hypocritical and deceitful<br>
i.	Desired unity, love, peace<br>
a.	Performed miracles signs and wonders (we must learn to live out the power of God in and through our lives daily<a href="43_14_12"> John 14:12</a>, <a href="41_16_17-18_20"> Mark 16:17-18, 20</a>) <br><br>
We must decide once and for all, will be respond immediately to God’s call upon our lives, to follow Him, or not. The decision must be firm, definite, permanent. The decision cannot be wishy washy, half-hearted, compromised, weak, indefinite, short-term. Some people will say ‘yes’ but mean ‘no’ in their minds and hearts. In order for anyone to properly follow Jesus, the decision must be to “repent” from the former things, and start on a new course, a new direction, a new way of life. There must be a change of heart and mind, there must be a letting go and putting off of the past. There cannot be a turning back or regret once one moves forward into the new way of life and living in Christ. <br> <br>

<b>Who Are You Following? </b><br><br>
It is important for you (and me) to ask these questions of ourselves. It is necessary to take some time to self-examine. Am I following Jesus? Am I a follower of Jesus? Is my life patterned after Jesus’ life? Are my values principles and convictions the same as that of Jesus? Do I search the Word of God to obey God’s commands and instructions? <br><br>
Am I following the world’s ways? Do I fashion myself after what I see and hear on screens (movies, internet, online chat applications)? Have I made the values of media become my values (drama series, journalists who report the news with their versions and views)? Do I follow well known personalities (politicians, movie actors, singers, dancers, performers)? <br>
Jesus left earth a little over 2,000 years ago and returned to His heavenly abode <a href="41_16_19">Mark 16:19</a>, <a href="42_24_51">Luke 24:51</a>. He commissioned His disciples to continue going about making disciples. Therefore today, we “follow Jesus” by following these: <br><br>
1.	The Word of God both Old and New Testaments as this is the will of God comprised and preserved for our knowledge observance and life. The Word of God is our manual of the life in Christ. There is so much treasure and truth in God’s Word. There is life and light and power in God’s written promises. We must search the Scriptures with a hungry and thirsty attitude to find the truth that will help us to live out this godly Christian life with success and fulfilment. <br>
2.	Jesus’ life as recorded in the books of the Bible written by His disciples Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John. <br>
3.	Church community – elders, pastors, brothers and sisters who fellowship and encourage one another. It is vital for a Christian to find a church community that is good and conducive for growth unto maturity. <br><br>
<font color="#ff0000">Practical - Prayer</font><br>
Practical steps include making a commitment to attend church meetings where the Word of God is preached and taught for the objective of helping you become a mature son or daughter of God. <br>
Suggested Prayer is as follows: <br>
Dear Heavenly Father, I thank You for calling me to follow Jesus. Right now, I decide to “Follow Jesus”, to obey Your Word, to stay in fellowship with brothers and sisters who together we can grow unto maturity. Help me to be a good disciple. Help me to learn Your Word, and Your Will, and Your ways. In time, help me to go and make disciples. In Jesus’ Name I ask. Amen.

]]>
</string>
<string name="Disciples_Self_and_Cross"><![CDATA[<b><font size="6">To Follow Jesus – Jesus’ Criteria”</font></b><br><br>
Jesus made clear to His disciples what His criteria was for them to become His disciples: <br>
&#8226;<a href="40_16_24">Matthew 16:24 </a> “If anyone desires to come after Me, <b>let him deny himself</b>, and <b>take up his cross</b>, and <b>follow Me </b><br>
&#8226;<a href="41_8_34">Mark 8:34 </a> “Whoever desires to come after Me, <b>let him deny himself, and take up his cross, and follow Me. </b><br>
&#8226;<a href="41_10_21">Mark 10:21</a>  to the rich young ruler, with a heart full of love for him: “Go your way, sell whatever you have and give to the poor, and you will have treasure in heaven; and come, <b>take up the cross, and follow Me.” </b><br>
&#8226;<a href="42_9_23">Luke 9:23 </a> “If anyone desires to come after Me,<b> let him deny himself, and take up his cross daily, and follow Me.” </b><br><br>
These scriptures were originally written in Greek and in translation, depending on what message the translator perceives the original Greek word (or writer) is attempting to convey, various English words can be used. Therefore, from the use of 3 Bible versions (New King James Version, The Passion Translation, and Amplified Bible), the following translations are listed and intended to give a fuller and better picture of Jesus’ criteria for His disciples to follow Him<br><br>

Another manner of saying “<u>to deny oneself</u>” is to <br><br>
&#8226;At once completely reject and disown one’s own life<br>
&#8226;Disown one’s life completely<br>
&#8226;Set aside selfish interests<br>

Another manner of saying “<u>to take up one’s cross (daily) </u>” is to <br><br>
&#8226;Be willing to share Jesus’ cross and experience it as one’s own<br>
&#8226;Offer oneself up to death<br>
&#8226;Embrace Jesus’ cross as one’s own<br>
&#8226;Express a willingness to endure whatever may come<br><br>

Another manner of saying “<u>follow me</u>” is to <br><br>
&#8226;Continually surrender to My ways<br>
&#8226;Walk with Me<br>
&#8226;Believe in Me <br>
&#8226;Conform to Jesus’ example in living, and if need, in suffering, and even in dying because of faith in Jesus<br>
&#8226;Become My disciple, believing and trusting in Me and walking the same path of life that I walk<br><br>

<b><font size="6">What Ingredients Comprises Jesus’ Criteria? ”</font></b><br>
The list of criteria as stated above may be self-explanatory. However, it may be worthwhile herein exploring and discussing the ingredients of Jesus’ criteria for His disciples. <br><br>
<b><font size="6">Lordship of Jesus”</font></b><br>
Firstly, let us explore and discuss “lordship” or “master”. <br><br>
The fact of the matter is that it is the lord or master that calls the shots; the lord dictates, he gives instructions. It is his will that is obeyed, it is his directions that are carried out. It is the disciple’s prerogative or right to call the shots, dictate, instruct, or direct. Amazingly, the heart of God towards His disciples is one of friendship and not ‘slavery’<a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/John/15/15"> John 15:15</a>. Because of relationship, despite His lordship, Jesus welcomes the disciples’ discussion, query to clarify, and quest to understand <a href="23_1_18">Isaiah 1:18</a>. However, the disciples’ freedom and ability ought not to be confused with opportunity to disobey, to be defiant, stubborn, resistant, absent and the like. One must remember that Jesus is on an overall basis, God, Saviour and Sovereign. He is worthy to be worshipped, reverenced and honoured. <br><br>
Therefore, the disciple must submit to the disciple maker, the Lord Jesus. If submission is missing, the walk with Jesus will be difficult if not impossible. A good example was the rich young ruler who after discussion with Jesus felt grieved and left Jesus, because He could not agree with and submit to Jesus’ requirements. He owned much property and had many possessions, which he treasured more than his relationship with God. He was not willing to sell all and give all to the poor. He preferred earthly treasures that was immediately present than heavenly treasures that would be in the distant intangible future <a href="41_10_22">Mark 10:22</a>. <br><br>
For the disciple, Jesus must be Lord of all, or not at all. Many of the disciples in the Gospels, even Paul in his letters, considered Jesus Lord, and recognized His sovereignty and yielded to His commands, His will, and His direction in their lives. <br><br>

<b><font size="6">Surrender”</font></b><br><br>
Secondly, let us explore and discuss “surrender”, which also means to yield, give in, relinquish control, give up one’s self independence to depend on another. The opposite of surrender is to resist, to rebel. <br><br>
The true-blue disciple of Jesus must properly surrender to Jesus. This involves allowing Jesus to be Lord over one’s will, desires, resources, ambition, and destiny; one’s whole life. The key to proper surrender is in the disciple’s knowledge of Who Jesus is, what is His nature and character. A wanna-be disciple must know Jesus’ loves for him, that He only has the best interests towards him. Jesus’ intentions for the disciple are only good and nothing evil or harmful. Jesus’ objective is to restore the disciple into the image and likeness of God, to build up the disciple unto maturity, to give the disciple great inheritance in God’s kingdom. <br><br>
Surrendering to the Lordship of Jesus, makes the journey of life walking with Jesus easy, smooth and joyous. The paths may lead to mountain-top experiences filled with wonder and glory, but may include valley experiences filled with great challenges, danger and fear. However, because of the disciple’s surrender, it is easy for Lord Jesus to lead and guide, teach and train. Even in the face of death the disciple can feel safe and secure because of Jesus’ Presence in life and even after one’s life<a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Ps/23"> Psalm 23</a>. <br><br>
<b><font size="6">Disciple’s Disposition”</font></b><br>
Thirdly, let us explore and discuss what is the proper attitude, mind and heart of a disciple, his or her inherent qualities of mind and character, which will please Jesus. <br><br>
The disciple must believe in the disciple maker. The disciple must believe that the disciple maker knows where he is going, knows what he is doing, knows what is necessary for the disciple to learn and experience because the disciple maker has seen what the final product will be, what the disciple will look like at the end. If the disciple does not believe in the disciple maker, s/he will form one’s own interpretation of events, one’s own perception of circumstances, and make one’s own decision whether to freeze, stay and fight, or turn to flight. In believing and trusting in Jesus, the disciple will wait for Jesus’ timing and decisions, the disciple will defer to Jesus’ better judgement. <br><br>

The Greek word for believe is an “active” word that involves action; it is not a “passive” belief where the disciple sits and does nothing. The believer of Jesus cling onto Him, believing fervently, connotes ‘force’ and ‘power’ that propels the disciple or throws the disciple forward to do good works as a result of believing in Jesus. This sort of belief and trust in Jesus enables the disciple agility to obey Jesus’ commands, to great exploits for God’s kingdom and His glory. <br><br>
The disciple must be humble, teachable, and available. God dwells with the humble and lowly, and the contrite of heart <a href="https://www.biblesociety.org.uk/explore-the-bible/read/eng/GNB/Ps/51">Psalm 51</a>. God gives grace to the humble person but resists the prideful person <a href="59_4_6">James 4:6</a>, <a href="60_5_5">1 Peter 5:5</a>. The disciple must be a good student, learning godly character and convictions. The disciple must be available, investing time and resources to know Jesus, and where He wants the disciple to go, what He wants the disciple to do. <br><br>
The disciple must be willing to conform to His example, to His way of life, to His instructions <a href="43_14_21">John 14:21</a>, <a href="40_28_19"> Matthew 28:19</a>. The disciple must be responsive and obedient to do Jesus’ bidding. God has already shared that He has no pleasure in the one that holds back or draws back <a href="58_10_38">Hebrews 10:38</a>. <br><br>
<b><font size="6">Disciple’s Sacrifice”</font></b><br><br>
Thirdly, let us explore and discuss the disciple’s sacrifice. <br><br>
Clearly in being selfish, the disciple cannot properly obey Jesus. Selfishness blinds one to the ways and purposes of God. Selfishness is contrary and will war against God’s will. A selfish disposition is totally and completely opposite to God’s disposition of generosity, giving, sacrifice. Selfishness is carnal, sinful, greedy, distrusting, inconsiderate of God or others and the like. <br><br>
The mystery of selfishness is that in gaining the whole world, one will lose one’s own soul <a href="41_8_36">Mark 8:36</a>. Jesus hints that there is no benefit in gaining all the wealth and power of this world, with everything it could offer you, its pleasures, at the cost of one’s own life. The gain simultaneously results it the forfeit and loss. The other mystery is that he who loses his life for My sake will find it <a href="40_10_39">Matthew 10:39</a>. He who seeks to live apart from Me will lose it. He who clings to his own life (soul, self, being) will lose it all. But he who lets go of his life for my sake and surrender it all to me will discover true life! <br><br>
The focus of self does not promote God’s will and God’s ways in our life. The disciple who is obsessed with self is distracted from focusing on God Almighty, the Source of life, power, miracle working wonders. When the disciple truly lets go of the hold on one’s own life, and let’s God take control of the helm and rudder, the disciple commences the walk of life where Jesus is at the helm and controlling the rudder. Jesus who is supernatural will naturally lead the disciple through experiences full of power and victory. <br><br>
The crucifixion of self that the disciple will experience is the discipline of God upon our lives. The experience may be humiliating and excruciating, but it is necessary so that self and selfish ways can be put to death and exterminated from the disciple, and also so that God has the power and liberty to create and fashion godliness and godly character within the disciple <a href="58_12_3-11">Hebrews 12:3-11</a>. <br><br>
<b><font size="6">Conclusion”</font></b><br><br>
Jesus willingly left His heavenly abode, His position and power, His glory, and exchanged His divinity and majesty, for a life as a man, to show the world the Kingdom of God, and provide salvation to all who would believe and trust in Him. While He worked miracles and amazed multitudes, He suffered humiliation, wrongful accusations, and death on the cross, because to Him, His disciples was His joy and prize <a href="58_12_1-2">Hebrews 12:1-2</a>. Jesus is the Author of our Salvation, and the Source of our faith. He is our example. His life must be the foundation of our life and the way it is to be lived. <br><br>
As Jesus’ disciples, we must be willing to obey His commands. Since He is Lord, we must yield to His directives and timing, in full belief of Him and trust in Him. It is our privilege to be able to walk with Him, learn of Him, and conform to His ways. We want to hear Him say at the end of our life’s journey, “well done good and faithful servant, enter into the joy of your Lord” <a href="40_25_21-23"> Matthew 25:21,23</a>. <br><br>

]]>
</string>
    <string name="Gods_Original_Intention"><![CDATA[
    When God created the earth and everything in it, He had an original design and intention for each component.<br>
    God created man (male and female) in His image and likeness, where man could think, feel, plan like God <a href="1_1_2">Genesis 1:2</a>. God breathed into the form of man the breath of life, and man became a living being <a href="1_2_7">Genesis 2:7</a>. <br><br>

    God\'s design and intention:<br>
&#8226;	For man to enjoy life in relationship with God, to rule the earth, to pro-create and fill the earth<br>
&#8226;	For fish to swim in water<br>
&#8226;	For birds to fly<br>
&#8226;	For trees to be planted in the ground to bear fruit and provide shade<br><br>
God blessed the earth, God blessed man and God blessed everything He created.<br>
God’s creation was perfect and harmonious.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="Satan_and_Demons"><![CDATA[God created angels first and then the Earth. Lucifer was the chief and leader of all the angelic beings. He was the most beautiful angel. He became proud and thought he was better than God. Sin entered his heart.
God being holy and could not allow sin to co-exist in His presence, He cast Lucifer and 1/3 of the angels who followed him out of heaven. Lucifer became Satan and the fallen angels became demons.<br>
These demonic beings only came to steal, kill, and destroy everything they could <a href="43_10_10">John 10:10</a>.<br><br>
Satan tricked man into disobeying God, committing sin, and took over man’s right to rule the earth.<br><br>

Man’s relationship with God was broken. He lost the right to enjoy abundant life and fell from glory.<br><br>
Problems then entered the equation: <br>
&#8226;	Internally: wrong choices, bad decisions, relationships, mental, physical, emotional, financial<br>
&#8226;	Externally: demonic attack, oppression, depression<br>
]]></string>
    <string name="Gods_Plan_to_Save"><![CDATA[From the beginning, God wanted to save man, reveal Himself to man and restore relationship with man.<br><br>
    From the beginning, man refused to respond to God (failed to understand, rebelled against, resisted, run away from God).<br><br>
    Therefore, God sent His Son Jesus to us – The Holy Spirit overshadowed Mary who was a virgin, and she conceived Jesus. Jesus was 100% God and 100% man. <br><br>
    God is one God but three persons – Father, Son, Holy Spirit. Just like man is one person but three parts – spirit, soul (mind, emotions, will), body (physical casing). The Son part of God became man.<br><br>
    Jesus’ came to reveal God’s presence with us, God’s love towards us, God’s power for us. Jesus came to bring Light and Life John 1.<br><br>
    God sent His Son Jesus to die on the cross for us. Jesus was the perfect sacrifice, The Lamb of God.<br><br>
    Because Jesus was 100% God He could not sin. Because Jesus was 100% man He lived fully dependent on and obedient to God, by the power of the Holy Spirit. He did not commit sin throughout His life.<br><br>
    Jesus’ death saved us. His bloodshed cleansed us from sin, covered us and made us acceptable to God.<br><br>
    There is no more need for animal or blood sacrifices. Jesus died once and for all.<br><br>
    God loves us. He gave. He did everything to save us, to open the way for us to have a perfect relationship with Him and eventually give us eternal life. Jesus is the way, the truth and the life <a href="43_14_6">John 14:6</a>.<br>
    &#8226;	We do not have to perform 100 hours of community service<br>
&#8226;	We do not have to inflict punishment on ourselves<br>
&#8226;	We do not have to pay any money<br>
&#8226;	Eternal life does not start when we die and go to heaven. Eternal life starts now. Eternal life is knowing God and living life with God <a href="43_17_3">John 17:3</a><br>
All we have to do is believe in our heart and confess with our mouth that Jesus Christ is Lord <a href="45_10_8-10">Romans 10:8-10,13</a>.<br>
That is all we have to do? Yes! That’s it!

]]></string>
    <string name="God_and_Man"><![CDATA[We just have to believe in our heart and confess with our mouth that Jesus Christ is Lord, and we are born again by the Holy Spirit who gives us new spirit with direct connection with God.<br><br>
After Jesus died, He rose from the dead three days later and returned to heaven to send the Holy Spirit to us. When we surrender our life to God, open our hearts, invite Him into our lives to live in and with us. The Holy Spirit breathes on us and fills us with new life. Just as God breathed on man at the beginning and gave him life, He will breathe on us and cause us to be born again <a href="">John 3</a>.<br><br>
&#8226;	Because of sin, the spirit in us is dead and separated from the life of God. When we are born again by the Spirit of God, we are spiritually alive and start to experience God’s life within us<br>
&#8226;	The Name of the Lord Jesus Christ is the only name by which we can be saved. He can help us overcome all problems and demonic attack<br>
&#8226;	Emmanuel is with us. The same resurrection power that raised Jesus from the dead is now present and actively working within us <a href="49_1_17-21">Ephesians 1:17-21</a><br>
&#8226;	God’s power is present and active within us to free us from all problems<br>
&#8226;	God’s power is present and active within us to free us from all demonic attack<br>
]]></string>
    <string name="What_Must_I_do"><![CDATA[This Gospel message is extremely good news. God’s kingdom is with you. Salvation is freely available to all. This life with Jesus and the fellowship of the Holy Spirit is available for sharing with you and everyone who would receive this good news.<br><br>
All you have to do is believe and confess:<br><br>
a)	Surrender all your life to Jesus – Ask Jesus to be the Lord of your life<br>
b)	Start to experience God being present in your life – Enjoy His life and power in you and with you<br>
c)	The Holy Spirit is with you, in you, and will teach you all things <a href="">John 14</a><br>
]]></string>
    <string name="Prayer"><![CDATA[<b><font size="6" color="#E90D14"> A. New Birth</font></b><br><br>

This is the prayer you pray if this is the <b>first time</b> you are opening your heart to God, to invite Him to come into your life and to walk with you.
[For the facilitator, as you lead the prayer for your friend, pause at every / to allow your friend to follow you in the prayer].<br><br>
<font color="#0DBAE9">So let’s pray:</font><br>
Dear Father/ thank you for loving me so much/ and sending Jesus to die on the cross for me/ I know I have sinned against You/ and I am sorry/ I ask for your forgiveness/ and I ask for the blood of Jesus to wash me clean/ I surrender all my life to you/ and request you to be the Lord of my life/ I open my heart to You, Holy Spirit/ Please fill me with new life/ Teach me/ lead me/ guide me/ transform me/ and make me into the person You want me to be/ Thank you Father/ In Jesus’ name I pray/ Amen.<br><br>
<b><font size="6" color="#E90D14">B. Put on the New Man</font></b><br><br>
This is the prayer you pray if this is <b>not the first time</b> you are opening your heart to God. You may have wandered away from God but now wish to renew your commitment to walk with Him, and allow Him to speak into your life through His Word and His Spirit.<br><br>
[For the facilitator, as you lead the prayer for your friend, pause at every / to allow your friend to follow you in the prayer].<br><br>
<font color="#0DBAE9">So let’s pray:</font><br>
Dear Father/ thank You for showing me the truth of Your salvation/ Now I understand that Your original design and intention/ is for me to live life with You/ walk with You/ experience Your presence and power in my life/ I know I have sinned against You/ and I have lived separate from You/ I am sorry/ I ask for Your forgiveness/ I ask for the blood of Jesus to wash me clean/ I surrender all my life to you/ help me to obey you as the Lord of my life/ Holy Spirit, please fill me, teach me/ lead me, guide me/ transform me and make me the person You want me to be/ Thank you Father/ In Jesus’ Name I pray, Amen.<br><br>
<font color="#B40DE9">Congratulations</font> on making the best decision to invite Jesus into your heart and life, and your willingness to walk with Him through life’s journey. May I encourage you to continue learning and growing as a Child of God because a great adventure lies ahead.
]]></string>

    <string name="WHAT_DID_YOU_RECENTLY_DO"><![CDATA[You attended a meeting full of Christians. They were singing songs to God. Someone shared life experiences and a few parts of God’s Word. When they asked for people to go to the front for prayer, you responded to the call to give your life to Jesus. What have you done? The people all about you were very happy and kept saying “you are born again”. But what does that mean?]]></string>
    <string name="WHAT_DOES_BORN_AGAIN_MEAN"><![CDATA[John chapter 3 records Jesus having a discussion with a Pharisee (religious teacher) Nicodemus, who taught, “unless one is born again, he cannot see the kingdom of God” verse 3. He was not referring to a person entering his mother’s womb a second time to be born. He was talking about being born of the Holy Spirit. Jesus explained that He was speaking of “heavenly things” <a href="43_3_12">John 3:12</a> and to Nicodemus “you must be born again” <a href="43_3_7">John 3:7</a>.<br><br>
Being born again is a very simple experience where one believes in one’s heart, and says aloud, “I believe in Jesus Christ who died on the cross and rose from the dead and is alive forevermore.” The Holy Spirit is the divine heavenly breath of life that gives birth to a new spirit within us. At the time of this occurrence, some people receive a tangible touch, some feel joy and some have no feeling at all.<br><br>
This is the heart of God as recorded in <a href="43_3_16_-17">John 3:16-17</a>.
God’s heart is full of love towards all the people in the world. He loves you deeply and has been watching over you. He patiently waits for you to open up your heart and life to Him. He wants to walk out this life with you!
This is the desire of God for family relationship with anyone who would respond to him as recorded in <a href="43_1_12">John 1:12</a>.<br><br>
God wants a personal genuine and ongoing relationship with you. Jesus’ Name was also Emmanuel, which means ‘God with us’.
]]></string>
    <string name="God_Jesus_and_the_Holy_Spirit"><![CDATA[
God is ONE in perfect unity. He co-exists as 3 beings; Father, Son and Holy Spirit.<br><br>
God is a SPIRIT being and does not have flesh and bones. He is invisible although He is a personal being with consciousness, determination, will, intelligence and feeling. He communicates with me spiritually and in <a href="43_4_24">John 4:24</a>, Jesus explains that we connect with God through worshipping Him in spirit and in truth.<br><br>
God is LIGHT and dwells in unapproachable light <a href="54_6_15-16">1 Timothy 6:15-16</a>. God is light and in Him there is no darkness at all <a href="62_4_8">1 John 1:5</a>.<br><br>
God is LOVE <a href="62_4_8">1 John 4:8</a> and out of love for us, God has sent His only begotten Son into the world, that we might live through Him <a href="62_4_8">1 John 4:9</a>, <a href="43_3_16">John 3:16</a>.
There are many truths to discover about this God. He is supernatural, omnipresent (present everywhere), omnipotent (all powerful) and omniscient (all knowing). God knows where you are and always seeking you. He knows everything and can do anything (well, except sin and the wrong thing) and even create something out of nothing.<br><br>
The Father is now our heavenly Father. He sent Jesus who was born of the Holy Spirit <a href="42_1_35">Luke 1:35</a> through the virgin Mary. She conceived the Son of God in her womb, who was called the Son of the Highest <a href="42_1_27">Luke 1:27,31</a>.
It was God’s earliest plans for Jesus to live on earth and experience every temptation known to man. Through Jesus’ life, mankind would learn of God’s will, God’s love, God’s teachings and God’s miraculous working power. This is especially so when God let Jesus died on the cross <a href="66_13_8">Revelation 13:8</a>, be buried, and resurrected from death to life on the third day.<br><br>
1.	Jesus died on the cross so that:<br><br>
a.	We are forgiven and redeemed from all our sins.<br>
b.	The sinless blood shed on the cross washes me, cleanses me, forgives me of all my wrongdoings, covers me and protects me<br>
c.	I am set free from every curse, bondage, disease, sickness, pain and suffering<br>
d.	I could be reconciled to Father God and be able to call Him Abba Father<br>
e.	I could start a relationship with Him with direct access to Him<br><br>
2.	God resurrected Jesus from death and grave so that:<br><br>
a.	Jesus could ascend to heaven to be seated at the right hand of Father God, and currently interceding for me and the world<br>
b.	Jesus could pave the way for the Holy Spirit (Helper, Counsellor, Teacher, House mate, Power bank) to rebirth many children of God<br>
c.	The Holy Spirit could make His home in me, live in me, and help me in every aspect of my life<br>
d.	The Holy Spirit would be poured out on my life to fill me, anoint me, empower me, live through me to do and accomplish great things<br>
e.	The Holy Spirit would restore my spiritual senses (eyes to see, ears to hear, tongue to taste, skin to touch, nose to smell), my mind to discern the will of God, and my heart to respond to God<br>
f.	The Holy Spirit would lead and guide me according to God’s will and way

]]></string>
    <string name="Next_Step"><![CDATA[Congratulations on making the decision to be born again, to become a Child of God, a Christian (a Christ-like one)! Now, let’s discuss your new life.<br><br>
Being born again is like crossing a bridge towards a new life. Physically, the current circumstances of your life probably remain unchanged; the same life, home, family, school, job… However, spiritually, things are radically different. You now have a new identity in Christ! Now, you ARE a Child of God with a heavenly Father and Jesus, your brother and friend. You have a Counsellor, Teacher, Guide and Helper! You belong to a new spiritual family with many brothers and sisters in Christ!<br><br>
Being born again of the Holy Spirit means you now have a new spirit with God’s DNA. His life is flowing in and through you, the blood of Jesus covers you, the Word of God will shed light on how you ought to live, and all of God’s heavenly kingdom is on your side.<br><br>
From now on, the old way is gone and the new is before you <a href="46_5_17">1 Corinthians 5:17</a>. You are in Christ! And in Christ, you have all the inheritance of God, all the resources of God, all the authority of God, everything that Jesus has accomplished by His life, death and resurrection. They are yours to claim! Does that make you feel special, favoured, blessed, loved or invincible? Here are some practical ways to jumpstart your NEW life:<br><br>
1.	Determine to stay committed to God, come what may, whatever happens, no “if” and no “but”. In whatever circumstance, your response should be “I love you God, I trust you completely, I will obey Your Word”. God will be with you and walk with you till the very end. He is faithful. He will never leave you nor forsake you. Keep fighting, till the very end!<br>
2.	Grow as a Christian. Remember that you are a newborn spiritually. There is plenty of learning and growing to do to be nurtured into an infant, toddler, child, adolescent, young adult and a mature adult. God has a good plan, a high calling and purpose, a great destiny for you. It starts with developing godly Christian character, maturity, and wisdom to make right decisions.<br>
3.	Start reading God’s Word, beginning with the books of John and Psalms.<br>
4.	Plant yourself in a local church that loves God, worships God, teaches the Word of God as well as relies on the Holy Spirit to lead and guide the church. Persevere even if people are not the nicest, even if misunderstandings and offences occur, even if you feel that things can be done better. The circumstances are perfect ground for you to learn Christian values, Christian character, God’s ways and how to deal with situations and live with others in peace and harmony. If you see a need, lend a helping hand. Serve and do what you can.<br>
5.	Fellowship with Christians who love God, His Word and His Spirit. They can teach and mentor you, walk with you as well as encourage and pray for you.<br>
6.	Discern and do what is right according to God’s commands.<br>
7.	Consider God’s Word daily. Learn of God’s ways and discover the truth about Jesus’ victory and authority, and your identity in Christ. Most importantly, enjoy the journey and watch your life transform. The truth gives liberty!
]]></string>

    <string name="DNA_Prayer"><![CDATA[In the writer’s opinion and experience, prayer is a wonderful (full of wonder) phenomenon and potentially an amazing adventure full of pleasant surprises, such as miracles!<br><br>
   As an introduction, let’s address some misconceptions of prayer. Prayer is not a one-way street, where one talks to God the ‘sugar daddy’ or ‘father Christmas’, whose sole purpose is to grant one’s requests. It is not true that God only listens if one is ‘good’, and prayer only yields results after one puts in the requisite action. Prayer is not penance done in fear, to earn God’s forgiveness and acceptance. One does not have to beg or bargain and use Christian jargon or bombastic language. Prayer is not boring, and it certainly is not the solution to insomnia. It is not all about ‘me’ and it is not only about the future. Scripture also describes what <b>prayer is not</b>:<br><br>
a.	Showing off to be seen by men <a href="40_6_5">Matthew 6:5</a>.<br>
b.	Vain repetitions that people use thinking they will be heard for their many words <a href="40_6_7">Matthew 6:7</a>.<br>
c.	Consulting with witches/wizards, mediums, evil spirits, omens for guidance <a href="46_10_13">1 Chronicles 10:13</a>, <a href="47_33_6">2 Chronicles 33:6</a>, <a href="23_8_19-22">Isaiah 8:19-22</a>, <a href="23_47_8-14">Isaiah 47:8-14</a> because God considers this to be an evil practice that defiles Him <a href="4_18_10-14">Deuteronomy 18:10-14</a>, <a href="3_19_31">Leviticus 19:31</a>, <a href="3_20_6-7">Leviticus 20:6-7</a> and is tantamount to witchcraft <a href="48_5_19-21">Galatians 5:19-21</a>, <a href="66_18_23">Revelation 18:23</a>.<br><br>

<b>What is Prayer?</b><br>
1.	Firstly, the most important foundational understanding about prayer is that it must naturally flow out of <b>one’s relationship with God</b>.<br>
&nbsp; a.	The Spirit of adoption in us bears witness that we are the children of God, adopted into God’s family, and God is Abba Father. We are confident in having the same standing as Jesus to inherit everything that belongs to God! <a href="45_8_15-17">Romans 8:15-17</a>, <a href="48_4_6">Galatians 4:6</a>. Jesus called out to Abba Father too <a href="41_14_36">Mark 14:36</a>. This Aramaic word has connotations of relationship and intimacy special to this family, and not shared with outsiders. Jesus gave us the blood connection with God, and the legal right to be placed into God’s family <a href="43_1_12">John 1:12</a>. It is out of this relationship with God that we pray.<br>
&nbsp; b.	We have access to the Father through Jesus Ephesians 2:18, John 14:6. We can enter the holy place by Jesus’ blood Hebrews 10:19-22.<br>
&nbsp; c.	Prayer requires a bit of time to align our focus on a loving God with proper communication.<br>
&nbsp; d.	Prayer connects us with our Father in heaven, who is Supernatural, Almighty and All-powerful. He is the Creator who creates things out of nothing. Therefore prayer connects us to a divine source of power. The analogy of an electrical cord being plugged into a power source in the wall, shows how power immediately enables the lamp to light up and give light. That is prayer; connection to power.<br>
2.	Jesus taught that the place where believers gather must be a “house of prayer” <a href="40_21_13">Matthew 21:13</a>. Since we are the temple of the Holy Spirit <a href="46_6_19">1 Corinthians 6:19, then individually, we must be a “house of prayer”. Therefore, prayer is imperative both personally and in the church community.<br>
3.	Jesus taught His disciples to:<br>
&nbsp; a.	Pray “to the Father” <a href="40_6_6-9">Matthew 6:6,9</a>.<br>
&nbsp; b.	Pray “in Jesus’ Name” <a href="43_16_23-27">John 16:23-27</a>.<br>
4.	Pray with the help of the Holy Spirit <a href="45_8_26-27">Romans 8:26-27</a>.<br><br>

]]></string>
</resources>